<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>RimSynapse - Psychology</name>
    <author>RimSynapse Team</author>
    <packageId>RimSynapse.Psychology</packageId>
    <url>https://github.com/RimSynapse/RimSynapse-Psychology</url>
    <modVersion>0.2.1</modVersion>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
        <li>
            <packageId>RimSynapse.Core</packageId>
            <displayName>RimSynapse - Core</displayName>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/RimSynapse/RimSynapse-Core/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly</li>
        <li>RimSynapse.Core</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>
        [h1]RimSynapse - Psychology[/h1]
        [b]📚 [url=https://github.com/RimSynapse/RimSynapse-Psychology/wiki]Official Wiki &amp;
        Documentation[/url][/b]

        [b]True AI-Driven Personalities, Dynamic Memories, and Evolving Mental States.[/b]

        RimSynapse Psychology leverages the power of Local LLMs to completely overhaul how pawns
        think, feel, and react. Colonists are no longer just a collection of static traits; they are
        living, breathing entities with deep backstories, evolving psychological profiles, and
        unique interpretations of every event on the Rim.

        [h2]Core Systems[/h2]
        [list]
        [*] [b]AI-Generated Backstories:[/b] When a colonist joins, the LLM weaves their vanilla
        childhood and adulthood into a rich, first-person autobiography and assigns psychological
        archetype traits.
        [*] [b]Nightly Clinical Evaluation:[/b] Every night when a pawn falls asleep, their entire
        day - average mood, survival stats, lifetime kills, and memories - is sent to the LLM for a
        formal psychological assessment across 8 categories (Relationships, Trauma, Satisfaction,
        etc.).
        [*] [b]Dynamic Memory System:[/b] Major events (raids, marriages, deaths, legendary crafts)
        generate personalized 1-2 sentence memories for colonists. Each memory carries weighted tags
        (e.g. [Food], [Resentment], [Combat]) and a decay rate.
        [*] [b]Desensitization Engine:[/b] The LLM receives a pawn's lifetime statistics (kills,
        damage taken, time as colonist) alongside their current psychological burdens. A pawn's
        first kill is traumatizing; their 25th is just another day. The AI decides.
        [*] [b]Defining Memories:[/b] Life-altering events (marriages, first kills, deaths of close
        friends) are flagged with zero decay - they never fade. These defining memories permanently
        shape a pawn's psychology.
        [*] [b]Tag Correlation Analysis:[/b] Instead of dumping raw memories to the LLM, the system
        aggregates memory weights by tag and reports top psychological burdens (e.g. "[Death]:
        Weight 8.5, 14 incidents"). This provides context without overloading the AI.
        [/list]

        [h2]Mental States[/h2]
        [list]
        [*] [b]AI-Driven Trait Evolution:[/b] The LLM can add or remove vanilla traits over time
        based on a pawn's experiences, sending the player a letter explaining the psychological
        reasoning.
        [*] [b]Functional Depression:[/b] Pawns experiencing extreme despair may still go to work
        and sleep, but completely refuse to eat, requiring immediate intervention before they fade
        away.
        [*] [b]Abandonment Risk:[/b] The nightly evaluation produces an Abandonment Risk Score
        (0-100). If it exceeds 90, the pawn may permanently leave the colony.
        [*] [b]The "Snap Out Of It" Mechanic:[/b] Driven by the pawn's traits, survival instinct can
        override extreme mental states if they sustain too much pain or malnutrition.
        [*] [b]Under Development (Debug Only):[/b] We are actively experimenting with highly complex
        psychological states, including "Suicidal", "PTSD Trauma Triggers", and "Reckless Euphoria".
        These are currently [b]disabled[/b] in normal gameplay but exist in the mod for testing via
        Debug mode.
        [/list]

        [h2]Interactive Psychology[/h2]
        [list]
        [*] [b]Player-Driven Therapy Sessions:[/b] Direct pawns to counsel one another on couches or
        chairs. The AI can autonomously generate a flowing dialogue between the two pawns based on
        their intelligence and ideologies, or you can step in with a "Guiding Hand" to type your own
        responses.
        [*] [b]Psychological Recruitment:[/b] Use the Therapy system to engage in deep conversation
        with prisoners, visitors, and faction leaders to organically sway their allegiance or
        ideology.
        [*] [b]Psychology Tab:[/b] Open the new Psychology gizmo on any colonist to read their inner
        thoughts, backstory, memories, clinical assessment, and full transcripts of recent therapy
        sessions.
        [*] [b]Visitor Backstories:[/b] Important NPCs (faction leaders, prisoners, royalty, family
        members) also get LLM-generated backstories during idle processing time.
        [/list]

        [h2]Default Settings (adjustable in-game via Mod Settings -&gt; RimSynapse Psychology)[/h2]
        [code]
        Memory Decay Rate Multiplier: 1.0x (Higher = memories fade faster, Lower = memories linger)
        Sensitivity Burden Threshold: 0.5 (Minimum tag weight before the LLM considers it a
        psychological burden)
        Enable Suicidal Behaviors: true (Sensitive content toggle - disabling removes all suicidal
        mental states)
        [/code]

        [h2]Requirements[/h2]
        [list]
        [*] [b]Harmony[/b]
        [*] [b]RimSynapse Core[/b] (Must be loaded before this mod)
        [*] A running local LLM backend via LM Studio or Ollama.
        [/list]

        [h2]Support the Project[/h2]
        If you enjoy the psychological depth this mod brings to RimWorld, consider buying me a
        coffee!
        [url=https://buymeacoffee.com/archdukejim]Buy me a coffee[/url]
    </description>
</ModMetaData>