<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>RimSynapse - Psychology</name>
    <author>RimSynapse Team</author>
    <packageId>RimSynapse.Psychology</packageId>
    <url>https://github.com/RimSynapse/Psychology</url>
    <modVersion>0.5.0</modVersion>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.5</li>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>RimSynapse.Core</packageId>
            <displayName>RimSynapse - Core</displayName>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/RimSynapse/Core/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/3760829776</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>RimSynapse.Core</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>
RimSynapse - Psychology
Official Wiki and Documentation: https://github.com/RimSynapse/Psychology/wiki

Companion Mod for RimSynapse. Requires RimSynapse - Core.
Brings your colonists to life by giving them evolving memories, complex interpersonal trust, therapeutic sessions, and trauma responses. 

--- Current Features ---
- Dynamic Personality Traits: The 24-hour psychological evaluation tracks profound life events. Pawns can dynamically gain or lose RimWorld traits (such as gaining Bloodlust after a brutal raid, or losing Kind) based on LLM analysis of their rolling short-term memory.
- Trust and Familiarity System: Replaces vanilla's rigid opinion system with dynamic Trust (-100 to 100) and Familiarity (0 to 100) values. Vanilla OpinionOf is scaled down by 50%, with the custom Trust metric contributing the remaining 50% weight.
- PTSD and Trauma Breaks: A new mental state, Trauma Trigger, causes pawns with severe negative memories to blindly fire their weapon at surrounding doors, walls, or loud noises before cowering in fear. Hitting a living creature snaps them out of it.
- Player-Driven Therapy: Right-click pawns to initiate a Therapy Session. Act as a "Guiding Hand" and manually type out the initiating pawn's dialogue, or let the LLM resolve the conversation in the background based on their Intelligence, Social skill, and Ideology.
- Opportunistic Euphoria: Pawns who maintain an extremely high mood (>90%) for a sustained 24 in-game hours will automatically generate a positive core memory.
- Ritual Remarks: Colonists pull from their LLM relationship memories to deliver personalized Vows during marriages and Eulogies during funerals.
- Forced Psychological Reviews: Demand an immediate clinical evaluation of the pawn's mental state from the LLM via the new Social Network tab.
- World VIP Backstories: Faction Leaders are no longer generic. They generate with a rich, ideologically consistent history and personality profile.

--- Planned Upcoming Features ---
- Couples Counseling and Dynamic Romance: Breakups and romances driven entirely by shared memories and psychological compatibility rather than RNG.
- LLM-Generated Phobias: Pawns who suffer specific traumas (e.g., severe burns, insectoid attacks) may develop targeted phobias that alter their pathing and combat behavior.
- Group Therapy: Let your highest-social pawn lead group sessions to mass-resolve colony-wide trauma after devastating events.
- Psychological Addictions: Pawns may turn to specific drugs as a coping mechanism for specific negative memories.

--- Changelog ---
v0.4.0
- Updated to support RimSynapse Core v0.4.0 (Multi-provider routing and Image generation).

--- Compatibility Matrix ---
- Royalty DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates memories of nobility and royal power.
- Ideology DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates crises of faith and spiritual rebirth memories. Required for deep Faction Leader generation.
- Biotech DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates genetic dysphoria and vat-grown trauma.
- Anomaly DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates void taint and cosmic horror PTSD.
- RimSynapse - Factions: Compatible and Optional. Empowers world generation to build deep psychological profiles and traits for Faction Leaders.
- RimSynapse - Chat: Compatible and Optional. Colonists' generated dialogue will be directly influenced by their current Trust levels, Familiarity, and accumulated traumas.
- RimSynapse - WorldNews: Compatible and Optional. Prints gossip and news articles about your pawns' most dramatic psychological events and relationships.

--- Requirements ---
- RimSynapse - Core (Must be loaded before this mod)
    </description>
</ModMetaData>
