<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>RimSynapse - Psychology</name>
    <author>RimSynapse Team</author>
    <packageId>RimSynapse.Psychology</packageId>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
        <li>
            <packageId>RimSynapse.Core</packageId>
            <displayName>RimSynapse Core</displayName>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly</li>
        <li>RimSynapse.Core</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>
[h1]RimSynapse - Psychology[/h1]
[b]True AI-Driven Personalities and Dynamic Mental States.[/b]

RimSynapse Psychology leverages the power of Local LLMs to completely overhaul how pawns think, feel, and react. Colonists are no longer just a collection of static traits; they are living, breathing entities with deep backstories, evolving psychological profiles, and unique interpretations of every event on the Rim.

[h2]Features[/h2]
[list]
[*] [b]Dynamic Psychological Profiles:[/b] Each pawn maintains a living "Journal" and a "Psychological Profile" that updates nightly based on their experiences. 
[*] [b]LLM-Interpreted Memories:[/b] A simple "-3 Ate without table" is transformed by the AI into a nuanced memory, shaping their worldview based on their existing traits and background.
[*] [b]Extreme Mental States:[/b] Introduces horrifyingly realistic breaks like "Suicidal (Burn)", "Suicidal (Starvation)", and euphoric "Reckless" behaviors. These are rare, trait-driven, and highly impactful.
[*] [b]Functional Depression:[/b] Pawns experiencing extreme despair may still go to work and sleep, but completely refuse to eat, requiring immediate intervention before they fade away.
[*] [b]The "Snap Out Of It" Mechanic:[/b] Driven by the pawn's traits, survival instinct can override extreme mental states if they sustain too much pain or malnutrition—creating dramatic, emergent stories of survival.
[*] [b]Interactive UI:[/b] Open the new Psychology tab to read their inner thoughts, analyze their mental trajectory, and see exactly how they view their fellow colonists.
[/list]

[h2]Requirements[/h2]
[list]
[*] [b]Harmony[/b]
[*] [b]RimSynapse Core[/b] (Must be loaded before this mod)
[*] A running local LLM backend via LM Studio or Ollama.
[/list]

[h2]Support the Project[/h2]
If you enjoy the psychological depth this mod brings to RimWorld, consider buying me a coffee!
[url=https://buymeacoffee.com/archdukejim]☕ Buy me a coffee[/url]
    </description>
</ModMetaData>
